fleeing from the Inquisition ,
the alchemist Uberto FuIcaneIIi
disembarked in Veracruz , Mexico .
Appointed official watchmaker to the Viceroy ,
FuIcaneIIi was determined to perfect an invention
which would provide him with the key to eternal life .
He was to name it ...
the Cronos de vice .
4 00 years Ia ter ,
one night in 1937 ,
part of the vault in a building collapsed .
Among the victims was a man of strange skin ,
the color of marble in moonlight .
His chest mortally pierced ,
his last words ...
Suo tempore .
Man : This was the alchemist .
The authorities located the residence of the dead man .
What they found there
was never fully revealed to the public .
After a brief investigation ,
the mansion and its contents were sold at public auction .
Never on any list or inventory
was the Cronos device mentioned .
As far as anyone knew ,
it never existed .
( tango music playing )
Man in distance : Only a few days left .
Tickets are running out for the big New Year 's dance ...
( clocks chiming )
Hey , how can I help you ?
- Good morning . - Good morning .
How can I help you ?
Old man : And this one goes ... where ?
V ery well .
Now it has a face . Well , you go next .
( both humming )
# When the sun rises in the morning #
# You open your eyes ... #
You still have this one .
Sort it out . By size and ...
lf you anger them it 's worse ... it 's worse , Aurora .
( hollow echo )
( phone ringing )
De la Guardia Company .
What did you find ?
Yes .
Right .
Another statue , huh ?
Fine .
I 'll tell him .
( beeping )
Ready .
( buzzing )
( opera playing )
Uncle ?
Ahh ...
lovely day for breakfast pills . Reds , yellows , blues .
And ... the new draft of your will , ready to- -
Shhh !
Why do you always have to be so noisy ?
Just sign the new draft of your will .
I have news for you .
Our buyer just called .
Papers .
- Thank you . - Now tell me ,
what did our buyer have to say to you ?
Oh ...
same old thing .
I found another archangel .
So what are you waiting for ?
No , not this time .
This time you get somebody else to pick up your garbage .
Not everything is garbage .
No , not that book again .
This is not garbage .
I know they all look the same to me .
That 's part of the problem . Open your eyes .
Look . This is different .
This one will be mine !
- Lovely day . - Good morning , sir .
Are you looking for anything in particular ?
- Pricey . - lt 's unique .
Yeah , sure .
They all are .
But ... then ,
it 's not my money .
Keep the change .
I 'll wrap it up for you .
I love these mirrors .
Do you want any ?
Yes ?
No ?
Yes .
May I ask your opinion about something ?
- Sure . - Yours too .
V ery " importante . " V ery important .
- Do you like this one ? - No .
- How about this one ? - No .
- This one ? - That one .
- Which one ? - That one .
You too ? Yes ?
Thank you very much .
You don 't know how important this is to me .
A little gift , thank you .
Thank you both .
Good luck .
No , honey , it 's not chocolate .
Something like this just happens once in a lifetime .
Once in a lifetime .
( winding )
( ticking )
Well ...
nothing happens .
( laughing )
Look , how curious .
What do you think it could be ?
A toy ?
Don 't get close to it .
Don 't get scared .
Bring me a box .
Woman : One , two , three , and ...
one , two ... one , two , three .
Now , watch carefully , this is seven by four .
We 'll start with this leg , Manuelito .
And ... one , two , three , and ...
four , five , six , seven .
One , two , three , four .
- Don 't push , Manuelito . - Sorry , ma 'am .
And ...
Now comes the finale .
( applause )
Good evening .
Where did you say you fell ?
Over some broken glass .
You won 't need any stitches .
Blood is so messy .
Remember when Aunt Marge died ?
Everyone was soaked in blood and she was spotless .
But really dead .
There 's something here .
It 's going to hurt .
Good thing you warned me .
Almost .
It was buried deep .
Man : What is it ?
Woman : I don 't know , some sort of metal shaving .
No , it 's more like a sting ...
from a bee , I don 't know .
( scratching )
Please , please , please .
Be very careful with my soul , please .
( ticking )
Our Father , Who art in heaven , hallowed be Thy name .
Thy kingdom come , Thy will be done , on earth as it is in heaven .
Give us this day our daily bread ...
( whirring )
( whirring stops )
I 'm fine , honey .
I 'm all right .
Good morning .
- l 'm reading . - There 's too much light .
It 's amazing , look .
Nena VizcaIna died at 92 .
Do you like it ?
- No . - You look ...
different , much younger .
Exactly , that 's why I did it . That 's how I feel .
Where 's Aurora ?
- You don 't eat breakfast ? - l 'm not hungry .
Hey , do you like it or not ?
- Yes , I do like it . - Well ...
that 's really nice .
( giggling )
DE LA guardia enterprises
( glass shattering )
Man : Hello , Mr. Gris ...
How are you ?
You ... destroyed my store .
I 'm not the one you want to talk to .
The red ones are especially good today .
You don 't know what you 're getting yourself into .
Almost 40 years ago ...
I found this manuscript .
40 years ago .
They are the notes , the hermetic annotations
of a 1 6th century alchemist .
It 's a fascinating book
written backwards in Latin .
It talks about a peculiar mechanism ,
an invention that extends its user 's life .
But it has rules , precise rules ,
very strict , on how to use it .
An insect ?
That 's the master stroke .
The insect is trapped inside the invention .
Like a sort of ... living filter .
You believe it ? I mean , after so many years .
Who says insects aren 't
God 's favorite creatures ?
Christ walked on water ,
just like a mosquito .
The resurrection concept
is not foreign to ants ,
or to spiders .
They could survive inside a rock for hundreds of years ...
until someone comes along and sets them free .
Sure .
It 's very educational , but I don 't see why you 're telling me this .
I 'm dying , Mr. Gris .
I 'm going to show you something .
The scalpel has been eating me alive ,
little by little .
Chemotherapy , radiotherapy , psychotherapy ...
Look closely , my friend ,
half of my body is here , inside this display case .
And the other half ...
it 's already in the menu .
Or it 's being chewed as we speak .
No. lt 's mine .
You used it ?
Just by accident .
What an imbecile .
Angel .
Angel : Here I am , Uncle .
Here I am .
Oh , Mr. Gris .
My uncle is getting impatient .
De la Guardia ...
We both lose something .
So ...
you finally got your ... whatever it is .
De la Guardia : Mr. Gris ?
You may continue the game .
After all , you have the toy .
But I 'm keeping the instructions .
And I won 't relent .
This can 't be possible .
It can 't be possible , damn it .
Aurora , my God .
Aurora ?
I know you 've got it .
Are you scared ?
You think something will happen to me ?
Are you comfortable back there ?
It already happened to me once , with your dad .
You remember him , at least a little ?
Yes ...
I believe you do .
When he was your age ,
he heard something or someone speak about those
who die of lung cancer .
So , when I came back from work ,
I found out that my cigarettes had disappeared .
After searching all day , I get in the bathroom
and I find a bunch of little bits of tobacco ,
floating in the toilet .
Just bits .
I think he understood that breaking my cigars
didn 't help the matter at all .
But at least it made it clear to me that he was worried .
And it made it clear to him that it made it clear to me .
You know ...
I don 't know what 's happening to me .
But I think it 's better if we stay together .
( metal slicing )
( ticking )
( knocking on door )
- Woman : Jesus ? - Just a minute .
- l need you to help me . - Just a minute .
Hurry , honey , we 'll be late .
Who are you , little one ?
A god ?
You 're so good to me .
Woman : I don 't understand why I can 't zip up this dress ,
it 's the same one I wore at last year 's dance .
I 'm almost done .
How could I change so much in such a short time ?
( applause )
( music playing )
Remember this ?
If I remember ?
# No , I can 't accept it 's all over #
# That life set us apart ... #
lf l remember ?
I always think about the first time I saw you ,
how I thought you would never pay attention to me .
I felt like such a nobody that ...
Man : That 's what architects call " vectors . "
It 's the little things that support the big things .
- How are they supported ? - The fact is that the pillars ...
- Teacher , can you see ... ? - ln a minute , Manuel .
- Cheers . - Cheers .
- Cheers . - Money and love .
Cheers .
- What 's wrong ? - Eh ?
- ls something wrong ? - No , I 'll be right back .
- Where are you going ? - l 'll get something to drink .
It 's the heat .
It happens to me all the time .
- ls it better ? - Yeah .
Every time I drink , I have to pee .
... since I was a kid .
What a decadent party , damn it .
Let 's see , let 's see ... fuck this .
Look at what they 've done here .
It must have been an Argentinean gate crasher
or some Peruvian on the loose .
Motherfucker .
I 'm working my ass off all year for a party ...
Let 's go .
Nine ... eight ... seven ...
six ... five ...
four ... three ...
two ... one ...
( " Las Mananitas " playing )
Radio : It 's been a pleasure , an honor for Radio dia ...
to bring to your home ,
the classic remote broadcast
of the yearly Tigers Club Party .
Always thinking of you ,
and wishing that all your dreams come true
and that all those goals you have set
reach the happiest of results
through the purest of roads .
Here , in this booth at HTLM
we feel honored , overwhelmed ...
Yes , why not ? Overwhelmed with joy
to be able to serve you , to answer your calls .
Mrs. Lorenza from La Colonia los Jardines de la Luz
sends warmest regards to all the family
and wishes happy times for everyone .
Mrs. Lupita Raquel sends us a wish
of glory to God in heaven
and peace on earth for the people of goodwill .
- How beautiful ... - We 're dead ...
Happy New Year .
Tell me where it is or my uncle won 't leave me alone .
What is it exactly ... this thing ?
What the fuck does the old man want it for ?
He never told you ?
You all think I 'm stupid , don 't you ?
He thinks that will help him to extend his life .
( laughing )
That fucker does nothing but shit and piss all day ,
and he wants to live longer ?
Leave me alone .
Do whatever you have to do , but leave me alone .
Of course , sir .
I will leave you , when ...
and if ...
it pleases me .
Get it ?
Get up .
( singing )
Fuck !
( bottle breaks )
How quiet .
All this blood , my God .
All this blood is mine .
I 'm dying .
How weird .
Everything is upside down
and I 'm dying ...
alone .
Alone .
Don 't let me die today .
Oh , it hurts so bad .
I can resist a lot longer ...
a lot longer .
Oh , Aurora .
( police sirens in the distance )
( ranchero music playing )
Great , Tito .
Great .
The forehead is coming out perfect .
Like nothing ever happened .
- lt 's your best work . - You bet .
It has its secrets .
Here I 'm giving form ...
texture ...
I 'm giving it color ...
They think I 'm a fucking artist .
Yeah ...
but don 't work on it too hard , we 're going to cremate him .
What ?
Motherfucker , what do you mean " cremate him " ?
You should have told me. I wouldn 't have dolled him up , fucker .
God , rest in peace .
It seems no one respects my work here .
Why don 't they tell me ? You , why didn 't you tell me ?
- Huh ? - The widow changed her mind .
It seems the guy didn 't have anything prepared .
No tomb , no grave , nothing .
They 're all the same .
Eternal , the fuckers .
Tape playing : Plastic surgery and you :
Plastic surgery , contrary to- -
( doorbell ringing )
Fuck .
- Yes , Uncle . - Get up here immediately .
Stupid-motherfucker-cocksucking son-of-a-bitch
asshole-pendejo .
- l want to know what happened . - l 'll be right there .
Shit .
I can 't blow this .
I didn 't touch him , the car skidded .
- Went off the cliff . - You imbecile !
( thud )
Uncle ...
What about his heart ?
What about it ?
Did you hurt it in any way ?
I told you I didn 't touch him !
His car skidded , it went off the cliff ...
Did you check his heart ?
It wasn 't beating .
Did anything accidentally pierce it ?
What 's the difference ? He 's dead .
It makes all the difference , all the difference !
Oh , you clumsy beast . You can 't do anything right .
After all these years I thought there might be hope for you .
But you 're useless , useless .
You probably ruined the whole thing by now .
How can somebody be deader than dead ?
You know nothing about dying .
I don 't understand .
No , you don 't understand .
And you 'll remain that way .
But there is one last thing you still have to do ,
and you better do it right
because I 'm not going to rest till I have what is rightfully mine .
And neither are you .
Look at you ...
( laughing )
Was the wake fun ?
You 're not going to heaven like that , right ?
Naked ... kisses everywhere ,
they 'll know you were out fucking around .
( gas hissing )
Come on , compadre .
Funeral director : ... 1 5 minutes ago .
Come in , this is your house .
Tito , Mr. de la Guardia is ...
was a friend of the deceased .
He wants to see the body ...
one last time .
Sure ,
medium or well done ?
- ( glass breaking ) - Ohh ...
( phone ringing )
Hello ?
Yeah ?
Jesus : Mercedes ...
( ticking )
( Aurora humming )
That 's for me ?
Jesus : Dear Mercedes ...
I write this lines with great difficulty .
( piano playing )
I want you to know that ...
somehow ,
someway ,
I 'm still alive .
And it hurts me to be alive .
The thirst is burning me ,
and I feel indifferent about everything ...
the day ...
this house ...
and you .
Aurora is staying with you ,
she ...
will leave you this letter .
By the time you read it ...
I would have been gone to settle some kind of date ,
an unfinished business .
Since I lost everything , at least I want to understand why .
Just today
I realize how much I miss you .
I hope to see you when I come back ,
and that you want to see me
no matter in what kind of shape I am .
Loves you ...
Jesus .
( thunderclap )
( echoing )
Aurora ...
My God , what are you doing here ?
I told you not to come .
Put that away .
Don 't you see they could kill us ?
Don 't you see we 're in danger ?
De la Guardia : It works ?
I knew you would return .
If you 're looking for the missing pages ,
you 're wasting your time . I ate them .
Best meal I 've had in years .
You talk about eternity , look at me , look at my skin .
It 's decomposing , it 's falling off piece by piece .
Peel it off .
What are you talking about ?
Look .
What 's happening to me ?
You 've been reborn .
( buzzing )
What the fuck is it now , you dried up old prune ?
What 's this , why the new skin ?
And don 't answer in riddles .
You talk about insects ,
alchemists , artifacts .
But what is it that I need ?
Blood .
Human ?
Of course .
You can 't gain eternity with a cow or a pig .
I can destroy the artifact ,
pulverize it .
As you wish .
If the device goes , you go .
But ...
we can share ...
- eternity . - What do I care about eternity ?
I don 't want to be eternal , I just want to get out of this .
That 's even better .
There is a way out .
But first , the device .
I don 't trust you .
I don 't see you have a choice .
Give me that , darling . Come on , I know what I 'm doing .
You first .
My way out .
As you wish .
You don 't even bleed right .
And now the heart ...
My God , Aurora .
Uncle ?
Talk to me ...
Let 's go now ... let 's go .
Please .
( clanging )
Merry Christmas .
( sinister laughter )
Mine , mine ... everything is mine .
Mine , mine , mine .
Angel ...
Enough .
You kept me waiting long enough .
( footsteps approaching )
You ...
Fuck ... not my nose again .
This has to end .
Oh , Mr. Gris ...
now I have to kill you again .
Ha !
Mr. Gris ...
Go .
Come here , precious .
Come here .
Angel .
What the fuck does it take to kill you ?
You 'll lose more than I will .
Mine is only pain .
Get ready for some more .
What the- -
Grandpa .
No !
I 'm Jesus ...
Gris .
Jesus Gris .
dedicated in MEMOR Y OF JOSEFlNA CAMBEROS
[ Ripped by Blink182 ]